Guide to the William Miller Abrahams Papers, ca. 1945-1998
Department of Special Collections
- Series 1. Editorial files
  - Subseries B. Business correspondence
    - Correspondence: T and V, 1962, 1965 (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence: 1965-1967 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: 1968 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: with the Atlantic Monthly, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: A, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: B, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: C, 1968-1969, mostly with Ann Cornelisen (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: D-E, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: H, 1969, concerning Lillian Hellman, Richard Hofstadter (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: 1969, William Inge (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: J, 1968-1969, mostly with Richard Jones (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: K, 1968-1969, mostly regarding Pauline Kael with some editorial material (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: L, 1968-1969, mostly with John Lehmann (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: M, 1968-1969 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: O-P, 1968-1971 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: P, 1969, mostly concerning Richard Poirer (Box 50, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: Rubin, Henry M., 1969 (Box 50, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: S, 1968-1969, with Francis Steegmuller, Jonathan Strong (Box 50, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: T, V, and W, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Woods, Gordon, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Zelver, Patricia, 1969 (Box 50, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: the Atlantic Monthly, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Belfrage, Cedric, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: C, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: D, H, and I, 1970, includes ts material from Lilliam Hellman, William Inge (Box 50, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: J, K, and L, 1970 (Box 50, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: S, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: M, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: P, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: unidentified, and photocopied review, 1970 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: A, 1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: B, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: C, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: D, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: F, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: G, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Hellman, Lillian, regarding "Collected Plays," 1971 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: I and J,1971 (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: K and L,1971 (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: M,1970-1971 (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: O, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: R, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: S, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: T, W, Y and Z, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: Field, Leslie. chapter outline for book on the history of Cartier, photocopies of newspaper articles by Field, found in correspondence file, 1971 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: A, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: B, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: C, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: D, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: F and G, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: H and I, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: K and L, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: M, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: N and O, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: P, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: R, 1972 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: S, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: W and Z, 1972 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: 1972 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: A, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: B, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: C, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: E, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: F, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: G, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: H, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: I and J, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: K, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: L, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: O, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: P, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: R, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence: S, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: T, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence: W, 1973-1974 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: letters to reply, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence: A, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: O, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence: P, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence: R, 1974 (Box 52, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence: Active Atlantic, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence: A-B, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence: C-D, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence: F-G, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence: Giberson, Dorothy. carboned ts, chapter 2 "Judith," found in 1975 correspondence file (Box 52, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence: Gleason, Ralph J.,1975-1976 (Box 52, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence: H-K,1974-1975, some Hellman correspondence (Box 52, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence: Johnson, Margot, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence: L-M, 1973-1975, ALS from Jing Lyman (Box 52, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence: N-P, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence: R-S, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence: T, V, 1975 (Box 52, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence: W, 1972-1975 (Box 52, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous replies and letter, 1974-1975 (Box 52, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence: Atlantic Monthly, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Mail to reply, 1975-1979 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: regarding Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston offer, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Decline, press and magazine, 1976-1980 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Hazzard, Shirley, and Steegmuller, Francis, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous letters, 1975-1976, Jessica Mitford correspondence (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous letters, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous letters, 1978 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous letters, 1979 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Letters to reply, 1980 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Hazzard and Steegmuller, 1979-1981, photocopied articles and reviews, 1970-1993 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: photocopied ts of several poems, author unknown, found with 1979 correspondence (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Judy Karasik, assistant editor, Holt, Rhinehart and Winston, 1980-1982 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, 1980-1982 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous letters, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, A-B, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, C-D, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, E-H, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, K-M, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, O-R, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Rejections, S-Z, 1980-1981 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: B-C, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: D-L, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: M-P, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: R-W, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: unidentified, 1982-1984 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums, 1982-1983 [one of two] (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums, 1982-1983 [two of two] (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums, 1984 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous editorial material found in correspondence file, 1983-1984 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: A-D, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: E-H, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: J-L, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: M-P, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: R-T, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: V-W, and unidentified, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous editorial material found in correspondence files, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: photocopied articles, reviews, etc. found in correspondence files, 1984 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: rejects A-B, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: rejects C-D, 1982-1984 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: rejects E-G, 1983-1984 (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: rejects H-J, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: rejects K-M, 1983 (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: rejects N-P, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: rejects R-T, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: rejects V-W, 1983-1984 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: rejects Y-Z, 1983 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: rejects A-B, 1984-1991 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: rejects C-D, 1983-1986, includes Connell, Evan S. Son of the morning star (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: rejects E-F, 1984-1985 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: rejects G, 1984-1986 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: rejects H, 1984-1986 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: rejects J-L, 1984-1986 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: rejects M-O, 1984-1986 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: rejects P-R, 1984-1986 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: rejects S, 1984-1986 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: rejects T-Y, 1984-1986 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, A-B, 1986-1987 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, C-D, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, G-H, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, J-L, 1985-1987 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, M-P, 1985-1987, contains AL draft to Joyce Carol Oates regarding first novel written as Rosamond Smith (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, R-S, 1986-1987 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: professional and personal, T-W, 1986-1987 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: unidentified, and miscellaneous editorial materials, photocopied articles, 1986-1987 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: correspondence of john Dean, editorial assistant to Abrahams, 1985-1987,contains reader reports (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous notes, editorial material found with John Dean correspondence (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence: rejections, A-B, 1986-1991 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: rejections, C-E, 1984-1988 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: rejections, F-H, 1987-1991 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: rejections, J-N, 1987-1991 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: rejections, O-S, 1987-1992 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: rejections, T-Z, 1986-1995 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: professional, A-L, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: professional, M-W, unidentified letters and cards, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous editorial material and photocopied reviews found in correspondence file, 1987 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums and material, 1985-1986 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums and material, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: A-B, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: C-E, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: F-G, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: H-L, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: M-S, 1987-1991 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: O'Donohue, Joseph J. IV, 1990-1992 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: T-Z, unidentified, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: editorial memorandums, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous editorial material found in correspondence files, 1988-1990 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: ts of untitled short story by Hutter, Stephanie, found in correspondence file, 1990 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: photocopied reviews found in correspondence file, 1988-1990 (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Folio: two ts copies of introduction to the Folio collection of American short stories, correspondence, Folio catalog material, 1996-1997 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: recommendation letter for Joseph (Chip) Long, 1994 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, editorial material, includes two notes from Joyce Carol Oates, 1968-1969 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, editorial material, 1968-1972 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, editorial material, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 7)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - O. Henry Awards: editorial material, photocopies of reviews and articles, 1986 (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, 1988-1989 [one of two] (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - O. Henry Awards: correspondence, 1988-1989 [two of two] (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - O. Henry Awards: editorial material, photocopied reviews, found with correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - O. Henry Awards: untitled photocopied article, found with correspondence, 1988-1989 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Dungannon Foundation award: correspondence, editorial material, 1986 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Atlantic Monthly arrangements, 1975 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Expenses 1968, photocopied ledger pages (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Author addresses West Coast and elsewhere [circa 1970] (Box 61, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Atlantic Monthly Press memorandums, etc., 1970-1976 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous memrandums, Atlantic Monthly Press, 1974-1975 (Box 61, Folder 9)
    - Editorial material: Atlantic Monthly book lists, 1976 (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Documents and memorandums regarding Atlantic Monthly pension plan, 1976-1977 (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Memorandums regarding editorial assistant Eric Goodman, 1977-1978 (Box 61, Folder 12)
    - Editorial material and memorandum regarding Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, Fall, 1983 (Box 61, Folder 13)
    - Editorial material and memorandums regarding Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, Spring, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 14)
    - Editorial material and memorandums regarding Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, Fall, 1984 (Box 61, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: memorandums regarding Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston benefits, expense accounts, 1977-1983 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Expense reports, 1977-1979 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Expense reports, 1979-1983 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: regarding Abrahams' resignation from Holt, Rhinehart, and Winston, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: regarding Abrahams' move to E.P. Dutton, photocopied articles and unrelated book reviews, 1984-1989 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Retirement documents and memorandums, 1984 (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Memorandums regarding health coverage, Abrahams' transition from Holt to Dutton, 1984-1986 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Editorial material for Abrahams-edited books, 1986 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: regarding Abrahams' imprint books, editorial material, photocopied reviews and articles, 1986-1990 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: memorandums regarding Dutton publishing, 1988-1989 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Editorial material regarding Dutton publishing, 1988-1989 [one of two] (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Editorial material regarding Dutton publishing, 1988-1989 [two of two] (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Publicity material, photocopied reviews, regarding Dutton publishing, 1989 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Dutton Laid to rest, 1990: correspondence, memorandums regarding Penguin USA takeover of Dutton (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: recommendation letters for Jennifer Callahan, Laura Levin, and Joseph [Chip] Long, former editorial assistants, 1988-1990 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous editorial materials and memorandums, 1984-1987 (Box 63, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous editorial materials and memorandums, 1987-1988 (Box 63, Folder 7)
    - Publicity material for Penguin contemporary American fiction series, 1987 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Subseries C. Catalogs
    - Little, Brown and Co.: January-August, 1980 [1 v.] (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Plume Books: May-June, 1994, July-August, 1994, September-October, 1994, November-December, 1994, May -August, 1996 [5 v.] (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Dutton Books: January-April, 1994, May-August, 1994, September-December, 1994 [3 v.] (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Dutton Books: May-August, 1995, September-December, 1995, May-August, 1996, September-December, 1996 [4 v.] (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Anchor Books: Books in Print 1993-1994, Books in Print 1994-1995, Books in Print 1995-1996 [3 v.] (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Anchor Books: February-May,1994, February-May,1995, February-May,1996 [3 v.] (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Doubleday Books: February-May,1994 [1 v.] (Box 84, Folder 3)
- Series 2. Trustee files
  The Trustee Series is comprised of two subseries, the Hellman-Hammett Literary Trusts, and the William Saroyan Foundation. Both contain correspondence files arranged in chronological order, with the Hellman-Hammett subseries also holding financial statements of the trusts in chronological order. In addition, the Saroyan files have photocopied newspaper and magazine articles concerning Saroyan or the Foundation. The correspondence files for both subseries retain Abraham's original order, while the Hellman-Hammett financial statements are arranged by the processor.
  - Subseries A. Hellman-Hammett literary trusts
    - Correspondence: 1986-1989 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: 1990 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: 1991 [one of two] (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: 1991 [two of two] (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: 1992 (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: 1993 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: 1994 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: 1995 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: 1996 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: 1997 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: 1998 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - photocopied report of Hammett's copyrights listed by Library of Congress Copyright Office, through March 15, 1985 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Hammett, Dashiell. Woman in the dark: ts produced by the Lantz agency, with correspondence, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Unused stationery of the literary estates (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: December 31, 1988, January 31, 1990, March 31, 1990, May 31, 1990, July 31, 1990-December 31, 1990 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: January 31, 1991, June 30, 1991-May 31, 1992 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: June 30, 1992, August 31, 1992-December 31, 1992, February 28, 1993-August 31, 1993 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: October 31, 1993-January 31, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: February 28, 1994-June 30, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: July 31, 1994-September 30, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: October 31, 1994-December 31, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: for year ending December 31, 1994, correspondence from accountant (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: January 31, 1995-March 31, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: April 30, 1995-June 30, 1995 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: July 31, 1995-October 31, 1995 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: November 30, 1995-February 29, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: March 31, 1996-June 30, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: July 31, 1996-October 31, 1996 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: November 30, 1996-March 31, 1997 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: April 30, 1997-July 31, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: August 31, 1997-November 30, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: December 31, 1997-March 31, 1998 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Hellman trust financial statements: June30, 1998-August 31, 1998 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: January 31, 1990, March 31, 1990, May 31, 1990, July 31, 1990-November 30, 1990, January 31, 1991, June 30, 1991-December 31, 1991 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: January 31, 1992-June 30, 1992, August 31, 1992, October 31, 1992-December 31, 1992 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: February 28, 1993-June 30, 1993, August 31, 1993, October 31, 1993-December 31, 1993 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: January 31, 1994-April 30, 1994 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: June 30, 1994-September 30, 1994 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: October 31, 1994-January 31, 1995 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: February 28, 1995-May 31, 1995 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: June 30, 1995-September 30, 1995 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: October 31, 1995-January 31, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: February 29, 1996-May 31, 1996 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: June 30, 1996-September 30, 1996 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: October 31, 1996-January 31, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: February 28, 1997-April 30, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: May 31, 1997-August 31, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: September 30, 1997-December 31, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: January 31, 1998-April 30, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Hammett trust financial statements: June 30, 1998-August 31, 1998 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - The fund for free expression award: correspondence, photocopied ts of letters of reccommedation (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B. Saroyan Foundation
    - Correspondence: May 8, 1987-May 11, 1988 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: May 12, 1988-September 23, 1991 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Photocopied will of William Saroyan, April 1, 1981, photocopied agreement between the Saroyan Foundation and the Fresno Metropolitan Museum of Art concerning Saroyan real properties in Fresno (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Photocopied draft of Rules for Judgement, Saroyan Foundation Award, photocopied newspaper and magazine articles regarding Saroyan, miscellaneous material (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: photocopied letters regarding legal dispute concerning Federal appeal of lower court ruling, Lucy and Aram Saroyan v.Saroyan Foundation, 1988, copy of brief (Box 71, Folder 5)
- Series 3. Hellman Biography files